# Alberto A. Lopez

www.albertoalopez.co mailto:me@albertoalopez.co github.com/AlbertoALopez

## **Summary**

Software developer with 2 years of experience developing business solutions on web and mobile platforms, from concept through delivery. Experience with modern frameworks and tools, knowledge of testing and continuous integration systems. Driven self starter that takes ownership over own learning.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, CSS/SASS, HTML, Java, Python, SQL

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Redux, React Native, D3, Node.js, Express/Loopback, Wordpress

Tools: Bash, Git and Github, Webpack, Chrome Dev Tools, Postman, nginx, Redis, PostgreSQL

Other: Photoshop, Sketch, HTTP/REST/AJAX, Continuous Integration, Unit testing, Cloud Deployment, iOS/Android

### **Employment**

### Web Developer @ BoboLink Media

January 2017 - Present

Assisted in front and back end development of a client facing e-commerce website for a hotel, as well as a React Native iOS and Android application for site staff and management.

- Streamlined development workflow by taking advantage of new tools, implementing regular code reviews/pull requests and writing technical documents.
- Increased automated test coverage by 100%.
- Increased performance of first time to paint by 25%. Identified render blocking code with A/B tests, performance profiling using Chrome DevTools.
- Led development of a cross platform mobile application, with features such as push notifications, websockets and real time data flow

#### **Freelance Developer**

January 2015 - Present

Delivered several CMS and static websites for small clients

#### Electro Optical Technician @ Newcon Optik

May 2014 - December 2015

· Assembly, testing and calibration of high end optical devices for the defense industry

# Project Manager @ 19gale Inc

May 2012 - April 2014

 Managed projects and accounts for a web focused media startup that successfully delivered several projects for businesses within the GTA

### National Statistics Officer @ Baha'i National Center

May 2012 - May 2013

- · Responsible for statistical analysis, data visualization and training of regional employees
- Produced data analysis and visualizations using Python, Microsoft Excel/Access and SQL
- Automated basic tasks using Python and pywin32

### **Example Projects**

Polling

https://shrouded-fortress-20795.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/AlbertoALopez/polling/

A voting app built on React, node and postgres, hosted on Heroku. Allows users to create, vote on and share their polls. User accounts implemented with google oauth2/passportjs.

# **Education**

Ryerson University - 2016 - Present Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

Wilfrid Laurier University - 2011 Bachelor of Arts - Economics